<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Amachine%20learning%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D50" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:machine learning&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=50</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/ciLALd0cqOhT5njWLQPZKJ/Ton4</id>
  <updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">431452</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">50</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.03550v1</id>
    <updated>2019-09-08T21:49:42Z</updated>
    <published>2019-09-08T21:49:42Z</published>
    <title>Lecture Notes: Optimization for Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  Lecture notes on optimization for machine learning, derived from a course at
Princeton University and tutorials given in MLSS, Buenos Aires, as well as
Simons Foundation, Berkeley.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Elad Hazan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.03550v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1909.03550v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04422v1</id>
    <updated>2018-11-11T14:28:34Z</updated>
    <published>2018-11-11T14:28:34Z</published>
    <title>An Optimal Control View of Adversarial Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  I describe an optimal control view of adversarial machine learning, where the
dynamical system is the machine learner, the input are adversarial actions, and
the control costs are defined by the adversary's goals to do harm and be hard
to detect. This view encompasses many types of adversarial machine learning,
including test-item attacks, training-data poisoning, and adversarial reward
shaping. The view encourages adversarial machine learning researcher to utilize
advances in control theory and reinforcement learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaojin Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04422v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1811.04422v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1707.04849v1</id>
    <updated>2017-07-16T09:15:08Z</updated>
    <published>2017-07-16T09:15:08Z</published>
    <title>Minimax deviation strategies for machine learning and recognition with
  short learning samples</title>
    <summary>  The article is devoted to the problem of small learning samples in machine
learning. The flaws of maximum likelihood learning and minimax learning are
looked into and the concept of minimax deviation learning is introduced that is
free of those flaws.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michail Schlesinger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Evgeniy Vodolazskiy</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1707.04849v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1707.04849v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.09246v1</id>
    <updated>2019-09-19T22:02:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-09-19T22:02:00Z</published>
    <title>Machine Learning for Clinical Predictive Analytics</title>
    <summary>  In this chapter, we provide a brief overview of applying machine learning
techniques for clinical prediction tasks. We begin with a quick introduction to
the concepts of machine learning and outline some of the most common machine
learning algorithms. Next, we demonstrate how to apply the algorithms with
appropriate toolkits to conduct machine learning experiments for clinical
prediction tasks. The objectives of this chapter are to (1) understand the
basics of machine learning techniques and the reasons behind why they are
useful for solving clinical prediction problems, (2) understand the intuition
behind some machine learning models, including regression, decision trees, and
support vector machines, and (3) understand how to apply these models to
clinical prediction problems using publicly available datasets via case
studies.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wei-Hung Weng</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.09246v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1909.09246v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.09753v1</id>
    <updated>2023-01-23T22:54:34Z</updated>
    <published>2023-01-23T22:54:34Z</published>
    <title>Towards Modular Machine Learning Solution Development: Benefits and
  Trade-offs</title>
    <summary>  Machine learning technologies have demonstrated immense capabilities in
various domains. They play a key role in the success of modern businesses.
However, adoption of machine learning technologies has a lot of untouched
potential. Cost of developing custom machine learning solutions that solve
unique business problems is a major inhibitor to far-reaching adoption of
machine learning technologies. We recognize that the monolithic nature
prevalent in today's machine learning applications stands in the way of
efficient and cost effective customized machine learning solution development.
In this work we explore the benefits of modular machine learning solutions and
discuss how modular machine learning solutions can overcome some of the major
solution engineering limitations of monolithic machine learning solutions. We
analyze the trade-offs between modular and monolithic machine learning
solutions through three deep learning problems; one text based and the two
image based. Our experimental results show that modular machine learning
solutions have a promising potential to reap the solution engineering
advantages of modularity while gaining performance and data advantages in a way
the monolithic machine learning solutions do not permit.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Samiyuru Menik</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lakshmish Ramaswamy</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.09753v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2301.09753v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/0904.3664v1</id>
    <updated>2009-04-23T11:40:57Z</updated>
    <published>2009-04-23T11:40:57Z</published>
    <title>Introduction to Machine Learning: Class Notes 67577</title>
    <summary>  Introduction to Machine learning covering Statistical Inference (Bayes, EM,
ML/MaxEnt duality), algebraic and spectral methods (PCA, LDA, CCA, Clustering),
and PAC learning (the Formal model, VC dimension, Double Sampling theorem).
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Amnon Shashua</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">109 pages, class notes of Machine Learning course given at the Hebrew
  University of Jerusalem</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0904.3664v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/0904.3664v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.04105v1</id>
    <updated>2020-12-07T23:10:51Z</updated>
    <published>2020-12-07T23:10:51Z</published>
    <title>The Tribes of Machine Learning and the Realm of Computer Architecture</title>
    <summary>  Machine learning techniques have influenced the field of computer
architecture like many other fields. This paper studies how the fundamental
machine learning techniques can be applied towards computer architecture
problems. We also provide a detailed survey of computer architecture research
that employs different machine learning methods. Finally, we present some
future opportunities and the outstanding challenges that need to be overcome to
exploit full potential of machine learning for computer architecture.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayaz Akram</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jason Lowe-Power</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.04105v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2012.04105v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.07492v2</id>
    <updated>2022-06-07T14:48:09Z</updated>
    <published>2022-04-15T14:48:04Z</published>
    <title>A Machine Learning Tutorial for Operational Meteorology, Part I:
  Traditional Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  Recently, the use of machine learning in meteorology has increased greatly.
While many machine learning methods are not new, university classes on machine
learning are largely unavailable to meteorology students and are not required
to become a meteorologist. The lack of formal instruction has contributed to
perception that machine learning methods are 'black boxes' and thus end-users
are hesitant to apply the machine learning methods in their every day workflow.
To reduce the opaqueness of machine learning methods and lower hesitancy
towards machine learning in meteorology, this paper provides a survey of some
of the most common machine learning methods. A familiar meteorological example
is used to contextualize the machine learning methods while also discussing
machine learning topics using plain language. The following machine learning
methods are demonstrated: linear regression; logistic regression; decision
trees; random forest; gradient boosted decision trees; naive Bayes; and support
vector machines. Beyond discussing the different methods, the paper also
contains discussions on the general machine learning process as well as best
practices to enable readers to apply machine learning to their own datasets.
Furthermore, all code (in the form of Jupyter notebooks and Google Colaboratory
notebooks) used to make the examples in the paper is provided in an effort to
catalyse the use of machine learning in meteorology.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Randy J. Chase</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David R. Harrison</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Amanda Burke</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gary M. Lackmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Amy McGovern</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1175/WAF-D-22-0070.1</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1175/WAF-D-22-0070.1" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Weather and Forecasting 37 (2022) 1509-1529</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.07492v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2204.07492v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.ao-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.ao-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.01866v1</id>
    <updated>2019-09-02T20:36:19Z</updated>
    <published>2019-09-02T20:36:19Z</published>
    <title>Understanding Bias in Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  Bias is known to be an impediment to fair decisions in many domains such as
human resources, the public sector, health care etc. Recently, hope has been
expressed that the use of machine learning methods for taking such decisions
would diminish or even resolve the problem. At the same time, machine learning
experts warn that machine learning models can be biased as well. In this
article, our goal is to explain the issue of bias in machine learning from a
technical perspective and to illustrate the impact that biased data can have on
a machine learning model. To reach such a goal, we develop interactive plots to
visualizing the bias learned from synthetic data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jindong Gu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniela Oelke</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">1st Workshop on Visualization for AI Explainability in 2018 IEEE
  Vis</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.01866v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1909.01866v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1911.06612v1</id>
    <updated>2019-11-12T10:49:55Z</updated>
    <published>2019-11-12T10:49:55Z</published>
    <title>Position Paper: Towards Transparent Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  Transparent machine learning is introduced as an alternative form of machine
learning, where both the model and the learning system are represented in
source code form. The goal of this project is to enable direct human
understanding of machine learning models, giving us the ability to learn,
verify, and refine them as programs. If solved, this technology could represent
a best-case scenario for the safety and security of AI systems going forward.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dustin Juliano</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1911.06612v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1911.06612v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.08801v1</id>
    <updated>2019-03-21T02:17:08Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-21T02:17:08Z</published>
    <title>A Unified Analytical Framework for Trustable Machine Learning and
  Automation Running with Blockchain</title>
    <summary>  Traditional machine learning algorithms use data from databases that are
mutable, and therefore the data cannot be fully trusted. Also, the machine
learning process is difficult to automate. This paper proposes building a
trustable machine learning system by using blockchain technology, which can
store data in a permanent and immutable way. In addition, smart contracts are
used to automate the machine learning process. This paper makes three
contributions. First, it establishes a link between machine learning technology
and blockchain technology. Previously, machine learning and blockchain have
been considered two independent technologies without an obvious link. Second,
it proposes a unified analytical framework for trustable machine learning by
using blockchain technology. This unified framework solves both the
trustability and automation issues in machine learning. Third, it enables a
computer to translate core machine learning implementation from a single thread
on a single machine to multiple threads on multiple machines running with
blockchain by using a unified approach. The paper uses association rule mining
as an example to demonstrate how trustable machine learning can be implemented
with blockchain, and it shows how this approach can be used to analyze opioid
prescriptions to help combat the opioid crisis.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tao Wang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10 pages, IEEE Big Data Workshops, 2018</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.08801v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1903.08801v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1707.09562v3</id>
    <updated>2017-10-16T11:13:32Z</updated>
    <published>2017-07-29T21:59:18Z</published>
    <title>MLBench: How Good Are Machine Learning Clouds for Binary Classification
  Tasks on Structured Data?</title>
    <summary>  We conduct an empirical study of machine learning functionalities provided by
major cloud service providers, which we call machine learning clouds. Machine
learning clouds hold the promise of hiding all the sophistication of running
large-scale machine learning: Instead of specifying how to run a machine
learning task, users only specify what machine learning task to run and the
cloud figures out the rest. Raising the level of abstraction, however, rarely
comes free - a performance penalty is possible. How good, then, are current
machine learning clouds on real-world machine learning workloads?
  We study this question with a focus on binary classication problems. We
present mlbench, a novel benchmark constructed by harvesting datasets from
Kaggle competitions. We then compare the performance of the top winning code
available from Kaggle with that of running machine learning clouds from both
Azure and Amazon on mlbench. Our comparative study reveals the strength and
weakness of existing machine learning clouds and points out potential future
directions for improvement.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yu Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hantian Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luyuan Zeng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wentao Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ce Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1707.09562v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1707.09562v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.07915v1</id>
    <updated>2021-08-18T00:57:06Z</updated>
    <published>2021-08-18T00:57:06Z</published>
    <title>Data Pricing in Machine Learning Pipelines</title>
    <summary>  Machine learning is disruptive. At the same time, machine learning can only
succeed by collaboration among many parties in multiple steps naturally as
pipelines in an eco-system, such as collecting data for possible machine
learning applications, collaboratively training models by multiple parties and
delivering machine learning services to end users. Data is critical and
penetrating in the whole machine learning pipelines. As machine learning
pipelines involve many parties and, in order to be successful, have to form a
constructive and dynamic eco-system, marketplaces and data pricing are
fundamental in connecting and facilitating those many parties. In this article,
we survey the principles and the latest research development of data pricing in
machine learning pipelines. We start with a brief review of data marketplaces
and pricing desiderata. Then, we focus on pricing in three important steps in
machine learning pipelines. To understand pricing in the step of training data
collection, we review pricing raw data sets and data labels. We also
investigate pricing in the step of collaborative training of machine learning
models, and overview pricing machine learning models for end users in the step
of machine learning deployment. We also discuss a series of possible future
directions.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zicun Cong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuan Luo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pei Jian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Feida Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yong Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.07915v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2108.07915v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.08908v1</id>
    <updated>2019-07-21T04:03:36Z</updated>
    <published>2019-07-21T04:03:36Z</published>
    <title>Techniques for Automated Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  Automated machine learning (AutoML) aims to find optimal machine learning
solutions automatically given a machine learning problem. It could release the
burden of data scientists from the multifarious manual tuning process and
enable the access of domain experts to the off-the-shelf machine learning
solutions without extensive experience. In this paper, we review the current
developments of AutoML in terms of three categories, automated feature
engineering (AutoFE), automated model and hyperparameter learning (AutoMHL),
and automated deep learning (AutoDL). State-of-the-art techniques adopted in
the three categories are presented, including Bayesian optimization,
reinforcement learning, evolutionary algorithm, and gradient-based approaches.
We summarize popular AutoML frameworks and conclude with current open
challenges of AutoML.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yi-Wei Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qingquan Song</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xia Hu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.08908v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1907.08908v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03120v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-05T20:40:05Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-05T20:40:05Z</published>
    <title>The Landscape of Modern Machine Learning: A Review of Machine,
  Distributed and Federated Learning</title>
    <summary>  With the advance of the powerful heterogeneous, parallel and distributed
computing systems and ever increasing immense amount of data, machine learning
has become an indispensable part of cutting-edge technology, scientific
research and consumer products. In this study, we present a review of modern
machine and deep learning. We provide a high-level overview for the latest
advanced machine learning algorithms, applications, and frameworks. Our
discussion encompasses parallel distributed learning, deep learning as well as
federated learning. As a result, our work serves as an introductory text to the
vast field of modern machine learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Omer Subasi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Oceane Bel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joseph Manzano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Barker</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03120v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.03120v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07090v2</id>
    <updated>2023-04-13T03:30:03Z</updated>
    <published>2022-05-08T03:47:30Z</published>
    <title>Parallelization of Machine Learning Algorithms Respectively on Single
  Machine and Spark</title>
    <summary>  With the rapid development of big data technologies, how to dig out useful
information from massive data becomes an essential problem. However, using
machine learning algorithms to analyze large data may be time-consuming and
inefficient on the traditional single machine. To solve these problems, this
paper has made some research on the parallelization of several classic machine
learning algorithms respectively on the single machine and the big data
platform Spark. We compare the runtime and efficiency of traditional machine
learning algorithms with parallelized machine learning algorithms respectively
on the single machine and Spark platform. The research results have shown
significant improvement in runtime and efficiency of parallelized machine
learning algorithms.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jiajun Shen</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Have error in experiment</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07090v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2206.07090v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1507.02188v1</id>
    <updated>2015-07-08T15:07:39Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-08T15:07:39Z</published>
    <title>AutoCompete: A Framework for Machine Learning Competition</title>
    <summary>  In this paper, we propose AutoCompete, a highly automated machine learning
framework for tackling machine learning competitions. This framework has been
learned by us, validated and improved over a period of more than two years by
participating in online machine learning competitions. It aims at minimizing
human interference required to build a first useful predictive model and to
assess the practical difficulty of a given machine learning challenge. The
proposed system helps in identifying data types, choosing a machine learn- ing
model, tuning hyper-parameters, avoiding over-fitting and optimization for a
provided evaluation metric. We also observe that the proposed system produces
better (or comparable) results with less runtime as compared to other
approaches.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Abhishek Thakur</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Artus Krohn-Grimberghe</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Paper at AutoML workshop in ICML, 2015</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1507.02188v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1507.02188v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1212.2686v1</id>
    <updated>2012-12-12T01:59:27Z</updated>
    <published>2012-12-12T01:59:27Z</published>
    <title>Joint Training of Deep Boltzmann Machines</title>
    <summary>  We introduce a new method for training deep Boltzmann machines jointly. Prior
methods require an initial learning pass that trains the deep Boltzmann machine
greedily, one layer at a time, or do not perform well on classifi- cation
tasks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Goodfellow</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aaron Courville</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yoshua Bengio</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">4 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1212.2686v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1212.2686v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1607.02450v2</id>
    <updated>2016-08-28T15:23:47Z</updated>
    <published>2016-07-08T16:55:31Z</published>
    <title>Proceedings of the 2016 ICML Workshop on #Data4Good: Machine Learning in
  Social Good Applications</title>
    <summary>  This is the Proceedings of the ICML Workshop on #Data4Good: Machine Learning
in Social Good Applications, which was held on June 24, 2016 in New York.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kush R. Varshney</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1607.02450v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1607.02450v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.01503v1</id>
    <updated>2020-07-03T05:26:02Z</updated>
    <published>2020-07-03T05:26:02Z</published>
    <title>Mathematical Perspective of Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  We take a closer look at some theoretical challenges of Machine Learning as a
function approximation, gradient descent as the default optimization algorithm,
limitations of fixed length and width networks and a different approach to RNNs
from a mathematical perspective.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yarema Boryshchak</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">9 pages 3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.01503v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2007.01503v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="68T07" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.04942v2</id>
    <updated>2020-02-24T19:13:28Z</updated>
    <published>2020-01-14T17:56:16Z</published>
    <title>Private Machine Learning via Randomised Response</title>
    <summary>  We introduce a general learning framework for private machine learning based
on randomised response. Our assumption is that all actors are potentially
adversarial and as such we trust only to release a single noisy version of an
individual's datapoint. We discuss a general approach that forms a consistent
way to estimate the true underlying machine learning model and demonstrate this
in the case of logistic regression.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>David Barber</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.04942v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2001.04942v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1906.06821v2</id>
    <updated>2019-10-23T08:26:31Z</updated>
    <published>2019-06-17T02:54:51Z</published>
    <title>A Survey of Optimization Methods from a Machine Learning Perspective</title>
    <summary>  Machine learning develops rapidly, which has made many theoretical
breakthroughs and is widely applied in various fields. Optimization, as an
important part of machine learning, has attracted much attention of
researchers. With the exponential growth of data amount and the increase of
model complexity, optimization methods in machine learning face more and more
challenges. A lot of work on solving optimization problems or improving
optimization methods in machine learning has been proposed successively. The
systematic retrospect and summary of the optimization methods from the
perspective of machine learning are of great significance, which can offer
guidance for both developments of optimization and machine learning research.
In this paper, we first describe the optimization problems in machine learning.
Then, we introduce the principles and progresses of commonly used optimization
methods. Next, we summarize the applications and developments of optimization
methods in some popular machine learning fields. Finally, we explore and give
some challenges and open problems for the optimization in machine learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Shiliang Sun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zehui Cao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Han Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jing Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1906.06821v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1906.06821v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1911.00776v1</id>
    <updated>2019-11-02T19:53:32Z</updated>
    <published>2019-11-02T19:53:32Z</published>
    <title>Ten-year Survival Prediction for Breast Cancer Patients</title>
    <summary>  This report assesses different machine learning approaches to 10-year
survival prediction of breast cancer patients.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Changmao Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Han He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yunze Hao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Caleb Ziems</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1911.00776v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1911.00776v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.13457v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T00:07:48Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T00:07:48Z</published>
    <title>Tuning Learning Rates with the Cumulative-Learning Constant</title>
    <summary>  This paper introduces a novel method for optimizing learning rates in machine
learning. A previously unrecognized proportionality between learning rates and
dataset sizes is discovered, providing valuable insights into how dataset scale
influences training dynamics. Additionally, a cumulative learning constant is
identified, offering a framework for designing and optimizing advanced learning
rate schedules. These findings have the potential to enhance training
efficiency and performance across a wide range of machine learning
applications.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Faraj</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">9 pages, 13 figures, 2 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.13457v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.13457v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.11819v1</id>
    <updated>2020-11-24T00:52:49Z</updated>
    <published>2020-11-24T00:52:49Z</published>
    <title>When Machine Learning Meets Privacy: A Survey and Outlook</title>
    <summary>  The newly emerged machine learning (e.g. deep learning) methods have become a
strong driving force to revolutionize a wide range of industries, such as smart
healthcare, financial technology, and surveillance systems. Meanwhile, privacy
has emerged as a big concern in this machine learning-based artificial
intelligence era. It is important to note that the problem of privacy
preservation in the context of machine learning is quite different from that in
traditional data privacy protection, as machine learning can act as both friend
and foe. Currently, the work on the preservation of privacy and machine
learning (ML) is still in an infancy stage, as most existing solutions only
focus on privacy problems during the machine learning process. Therefore, a
comprehensive study on the privacy preservation problems and machine learning
is required. This paper surveys the state of the art in privacy issues and
solutions for machine learning. The survey covers three categories of
interactions between privacy and machine learning: (i) private machine
learning, (ii) machine learning aided privacy protection, and (iii) machine
learning-based privacy attack and corresponding protection schemes. The current
research progress in each category is reviewed and the key challenges are
identified. Finally, based on our in-depth analysis of the area of privacy and
machine learning, we point out future research directions in this field.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Bo Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ming Ding</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sina Shaham</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenny Rahayu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Farhad Farokhi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zihuai Lin</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">This work is accepted by ACM Computing Surveys</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.11819v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2011.11819v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2009.11087v1</id>
    <updated>2020-09-23T12:14:05Z</updated>
    <published>2020-09-23T12:14:05Z</published>
    <title>Probabilistic Machine Learning for Healthcare</title>
    <summary>  Machine learning can be used to make sense of healthcare data. Probabilistic
machine learning models help provide a complete picture of observed data in
healthcare. In this review, we examine how probabilistic machine learning can
advance healthcare. We consider challenges in the predictive model building
pipeline where probabilistic models can be beneficial including calibration and
missing data. Beyond predictive models, we also investigate the utility of
probabilistic machine learning models in phenotyping, in generative models for
clinical use cases, and in reinforcement learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Irene Y. Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shalmali Joshi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marzyeh Ghassemi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rajesh Ranganath</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Annual Reviews of Biomedical Data Science 2021</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2009.11087v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2009.11087v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.18087v1</id>
    <updated>2023-03-31T14:24:06Z</updated>
    <published>2023-03-31T14:24:06Z</published>
    <title>Evaluation Challenges for Geospatial ML</title>
    <summary>  As geospatial machine learning models and maps derived from their predictions
are increasingly used for downstream analyses in science and policy, it is
imperative to evaluate their accuracy and applicability. Geospatial machine
learning has key distinctions from other learning paradigms, and as such, the
correct way to measure performance of spatial machine learning outputs has been
a topic of debate. In this paper, I delineate unique challenges of model
evaluation for geospatial machine learning with global or remotely sensed
datasets, culminating in concrete takeaways to improve evaluations of
geospatial model performance.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Esther Rolf</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">ICLR 2023 Workshop on Machine Learning for Remote Sensing</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.18087v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2303.18087v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.11351v2</id>
    <updated>2024-03-31T00:32:13Z</updated>
    <published>2024-01-21T00:19:16Z</published>
    <title>A comprehensive review of Quantum Machine Learning: from NISQ to Fault
  Tolerance</title>
    <summary>  Quantum machine learning, which involves running machine learning algorithms
on quantum devices, has garnered significant attention in both academic and
business circles. In this paper, we offer a comprehensive and unbiased review
of the various concepts that have emerged in the field of quantum machine
learning. This includes techniques used in Noisy Intermediate-Scale Quantum
(NISQ) technologies and approaches for algorithms compatible with
fault-tolerant quantum computing hardware. Our review covers fundamental
concepts, algorithms, and the statistical learning theory pertinent to quantum
machine learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yunfei Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Junyu Liu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1088/1361-6633/ad7f69</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1361-6633/ad7f69" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">28 pages. Invited review</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Rep. Prog. Phys. 87 116402, 2024</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.11351v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.11351v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2004.00993v2</id>
    <updated>2020-04-05T17:16:23Z</updated>
    <published>2020-03-31T18:08:23Z</published>
    <title>Augmented Q Imitation Learning (AQIL)</title>
    <summary>  The study of unsupervised learning can be generally divided into two
categories: imitation learning and reinforcement learning. In imitation
learning the machine learns by mimicking the behavior of an expert system
whereas in reinforcement learning the machine learns via direct environment
feedback. Traditional deep reinforcement learning takes a significant time
before the machine starts to converge to an optimal policy. This paper proposes
Augmented Q-Imitation-Learning, a method by which deep reinforcement learning
convergence can be accelerated by applying Q-imitation-learning as the initial
training process in traditional Deep Q-learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xiao Lei Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anish Agarwal</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">5 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2004.00993v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2004.00993v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.05155v2</id>
    <updated>2021-02-24T14:33:24Z</updated>
    <published>2020-03-11T08:25:49Z</published>
    <title>Towards CRISP-ML(Q): A Machine Learning Process Model with Quality
  Assurance Methodology</title>
    <summary>  Machine learning is an established and frequently used technique in industry
and academia but a standard process model to improve success and efficiency of
machine learning applications is still missing. Project organizations and
machine learning practitioners have a need for guidance throughout the life
cycle of a machine learning application to meet business expectations. We
therefore propose a process model for the development of machine learning
applications, that covers six phases from defining the scope to maintaining the
deployed machine learning application. The first phase combines business and
data understanding as data availability oftentimes affects the feasibility of
the project. The sixth phase covers state-of-the-art approaches for monitoring
and maintenance of a machine learning applications, as the risk of model
degradation in a changing environment is eminent. With each task of the
process, we propose quality assurance methodology that is suitable to adress
challenges in machine learning development that we identify in form of risks.
The methodology is drawn from practical experience and scientific literature
and has proven to be general and stable. The process model expands on CRISP-DM,
a data mining process model that enjoys strong industry support but lacks to
address machine learning specific tasks. Our work proposes an industry and
application neutral process model tailored for machine learning applications
with focus on technical tasks for quality assurance.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Stefan Studer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thanh Binh Bui</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christian Drescher</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Hanuschkin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ludwig Winkler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Steven Peters</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Klaus-Robert Mueller</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Machine Learning Applications, Quality Assurance Methodology, Process
  Model, Best Practices for Machine Learning Applications, Automotive Industry
  and Academia, Best Practices, Guidelines</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.05155v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2003.05155v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1706.08001v1</id>
    <updated>2017-06-24T20:56:27Z</updated>
    <published>2017-06-24T20:56:27Z</published>
    <title>Temporal-related Convolutional-Restricted-Boltzmann-Machine capable of
  learning relational order via reinforcement learning procedure?</title>
    <summary>  In this article, we extend the conventional framework of
convolutional-Restricted-Boltzmann-Machine to learn highly abstract features
among abitrary number of time related input maps by constructing a layer of
multiplicative units, which capture the relations among inputs. In many cases,
more than two maps are strongly related, so it is wise to make multiplicative
unit learn relations among more input maps, in other words, to find the optimal
relational-order of each unit. In order to enable our machine to learn
relational order, we developed a reinforcement-learning method whose optimality
is proven to train the network.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zizhuang Wang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Keywords: Convolutional-Restricted-Boltzmann-Machine, Reinforcement
  learning</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1706.08001v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.08001v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03720v1</id>
    <updated>2024-05-05T20:39:15Z</updated>
    <published>2024-05-05T20:39:15Z</published>
    <title>Spatial Transfer Learning with Simple MLP</title>
    <summary>  First step to investigate the potential of transfer learning applied to the
field of spatial statistics
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hongjian Yang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03720v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2405.03720v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.4676v2</id>
    <updated>2012-09-16T11:24:54Z</updated>
    <published>2012-07-19T14:08:22Z</published>
    <title>Proceedings of the 29th International Conference on Machine Learning
  (ICML-12)</title>
    <summary>  This is an index to the papers that appear in the Proceedings of the 29th
International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML-12). The conference was held
in Edinburgh, Scotland, June 27th - July 3rd, 2012.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>John Langford</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Editors</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joelle Pineau</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Editors</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Proceedings of the 29th International Conference on Machine Learning
  (ICML-12). Editors: John Langford and Joelle Pineau. Publisher: Omnipress,
  2012</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.4676v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1207.4676v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1603.02185v1</id>
    <updated>2016-03-07T18:11:54Z</updated>
    <published>2016-03-07T18:11:54Z</published>
    <title>Distributed Multi-Task Learning with Shared Representation</title>
    <summary>  We study the problem of distributed multi-task learning with shared
representation, where each machine aims to learn a separate, but related, task
in an unknown shared low-dimensional subspaces, i.e. when the predictor matrix
has low rank. We consider a setting where each task is handled by a different
machine, with samples for the task available locally on the machine, and study
communication-efficient methods for exploiting the shared structure.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jialei Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mladen Kolar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Srebro</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1603.02185v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1603.02185v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1910.12387v2</id>
    <updated>2019-10-30T07:59:02Z</updated>
    <published>2019-10-25T17:33:33Z</published>
    <title>Components of Machine Learning: Binding Bits and FLOPS</title>
    <summary>  Many machine learning problems and methods are combinations of three
components: data, hypothesis space and loss function. Different machine
learning methods are obtained as combinations of different choices for the
representation of data, hypothesis space and loss function. After reviewing the
mathematical structure of these three components, we discuss intrinsic
trade-offs between statistical and computational properties of machine learning
methods.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Jung</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1910.12387v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1910.12387v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.05479v1</id>
    <updated>2020-07-10T16:57:18Z</updated>
    <published>2020-07-10T16:57:18Z</published>
    <title>Impact of Legal Requirements on Explainability in Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  The requirements on explainability imposed by European laws and their
implications for machine learning (ML) models are not always clear. In that
perspective, our research analyzes explanation obligations imposed for private
and public decision-making, and how they can be implemented by machine learning
techniques.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Adrien Bibal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Lognoul</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexandre de Streel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benot Frnay</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">ICML Workshop on Law and Machine Learning</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.05479v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2007.05479v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.14206v1</id>
    <updated>2020-07-27T14:30:23Z</updated>
    <published>2020-07-27T14:30:23Z</published>
    <title>Machine Learning Potential Repository</title>
    <summary>  This paper introduces a machine learning potential repository that includes
Pareto optimal machine learning potentials. It also shows the systematic
development of accurate and fast machine learning potentials for a wide range
of elemental systems. As a result, many Pareto optimal machine learning
potentials are available in the repository from a website. Therefore, the
repository will help many scientists to perform accurate and fast atomistic
simulations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Atsuto Seko</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">9 pages, 3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.14206v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2007.14206v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18979v1</id>
    <updated>2024-12-25T20:21:24Z</updated>
    <published>2024-12-25T20:21:24Z</published>
    <title>Quantum memristors for neuromorphic quantum machine learning</title>
    <summary>  Quantum machine learning may permit to realize more efficient machine
learning calculations with near-term quantum devices. Among the diverse quantum
machine learning paradigms which are currently being considered, quantum
memristors are promising as a way of combining, in the same quantum hardware, a
unitary evolution with the nonlinearity provided by the measurement and
feedforward. Thus, an efficient way of deploying neuromorphic quantum computing
for quantum machine learning may be enabled.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lucas Lamata</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Invited Perspective</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18979v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2412.18979v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1908.04710v3</id>
    <updated>2020-07-27T14:47:52Z</updated>
    <published>2019-08-13T15:52:31Z</published>
    <title>metric-learn: Metric Learning Algorithms in Python</title>
    <summary>  metric-learn is an open source Python package implementing supervised and
weakly-supervised distance metric learning algorithms. As part of
scikit-learn-contrib, it provides a unified interface compatible with
scikit-learn which allows to easily perform cross-validation, model selection,
and pipelining with other machine learning estimators. metric-learn is
thoroughly tested and available on PyPi under the MIT licence.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>William de Vazelhes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>CJ Carey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuan Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nathalie Vauquier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aurlien Bellet</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">GitHub repository:
  https://github.com/scikit-learn-contrib/metric-learn</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Journal of Machine Learning Research (JMLR), 21(138):1-6, 2020</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1908.04710v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1908.04710v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.12364v1</id>
    <updated>2020-02-27T13:35:26Z</updated>
    <published>2020-02-27T13:35:26Z</published>
    <title>Theoretical Models of Learning to Learn</title>
    <summary>  A Machine can only learn if it is biased in some way. Typically the bias is
supplied by hand, for example through the choice of an appropriate set of
features. However, if the learning machine is embedded within an {\em
environment} of related tasks, then it can {\em learn} its own bias by learning
sufficiently many tasks from the environment. In this paper two models of bias
learning (or equivalently, learning to learn) are introduced and the main
theoretical results presented. The first model is a PAC-type model based on
empirical process theory, while the second is a hierarchical Bayes model.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan Baxter</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1007/978-1-4615-5529-2</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4615-5529-2" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1106.0245</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">in Learning to Learn (edited by Sebastian Thrun and Lorien Pratt),
  159-179 (1998)</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.12364v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.12364v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1607.01400v1</id>
    <updated>2016-07-05T20:04:57Z</updated>
    <published>2016-07-05T20:04:57Z</published>
    <title>An Aggregate and Iterative Disaggregate Algorithm with Proven Optimality
  in Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  We propose a clustering-based iterative algorithm to solve certain
optimization problems in machine learning, where we start the algorithm by
aggregating the original data, solving the problem on aggregated data, and then
in subsequent steps gradually disaggregate the aggregated data. We apply the
algorithm to common machine learning problems such as the least absolute
deviation regression problem, support vector machines, and semi-supervised
support vector machines. We derive model-specific data aggregation and
disaggregation procedures. We also show optimality, convergence, and the
optimality gap of the approximated solution in each iteration. A computational
study is provided.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Young Woong Park</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Diego Klabjan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1007/s10994-016-5562-z</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10994-016-5562-z" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Machine Learning 105 (2016) 199 - 232</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1607.01400v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1607.01400v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.10564v1</id>
    <updated>2022-02-21T22:45:59Z</updated>
    <published>2022-02-21T22:45:59Z</published>
    <title>Human-in-the-loop Machine Learning: A Macro-Micro Perspective</title>
    <summary>  Though technical advance of artificial intelligence and machine learning has
enabled many promising intelligent systems, many computing tasks are still not
able to be fully accomplished by machine intelligence. Motivated by the
complementary nature of human and machine intelligence, an emerging trend is to
involve humans in the loop of machine learning and decision-making. In this
paper, we provide a macro-micro review of human-in-the-loop machine learning.
We first describe major machine learning challenges which can be addressed by
human intervention in the loop. Then we examine closely the latest research and
findings of introducing humans into each step of the lifecycle of machine
learning. Finally, we analyze current research gaps and point out future
research directions.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jiangtao Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bin Guo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liming Chen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.10564v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2202.10564v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05526v1</id>
    <updated>2024-07-08T00:19:43Z</updated>
    <published>2024-07-08T00:19:43Z</published>
    <title>Can Machines Learn the True Probabilities?</title>
    <summary>  When there exists uncertainty, AI machines are designed to make decisions so
as to reach the best expected outcomes. Expectations are based on true facts
about the objective environment the machines interact with, and those facts can
be encoded into AI models in the form of true objective probability functions.
Accordingly, AI models involve probabilistic machine learning in which the
probabilities should be objectively interpreted. We prove under some basic
assumptions when machines can learn the true objective probabilities, if any,
and when machines cannot learn them.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jinsook Kim</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05526v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2407.05526v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1509.00913v3</id>
    <updated>2015-09-29T16:57:42Z</updated>
    <published>2015-09-03T01:30:29Z</published>
    <title>On-the-Fly Learning in a Perpetual Learning Machine</title>
    <summary>  Despite the promise of brain-inspired machine learning, deep neural networks
(DNN) have frustratingly failed to bridge the deceptively large gap between
learning and memory. Here, we introduce a Perpetual Learning Machine; a new
type of DNN that is capable of brain-like dynamic 'on the fly' learning because
it exists in a self-supervised state of Perpetual Stochastic Gradient Descent.
Thus, we provide the means to unify learning and memory within a machine
learning framework. We also explore the elegant duality of abstraction and
synthesis: the Yin and Yang of deep learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. R. Simpson</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1509.00913v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1509.00913v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="68Txx" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.12773v1</id>
    <updated>2021-10-25T10:05:11Z</updated>
    <published>2021-10-25T10:05:11Z</published>
    <title>Scientific Machine Learning Benchmarks</title>
    <summary>  The breakthrough in Deep Learning neural networks has transformed the use of
AI and machine learning technologies for the analysis of very large
experimental datasets. These datasets are typically generated by large-scale
experimental facilities at national laboratories. In the context of science,
scientific machine learning focuses on training machines to identify patterns,
trends, and anomalies to extract meaningful scientific insights from such
datasets. With a new generation of experimental facilities, the rate of data
generation and the scale of data volumes will increasingly require the use of
more automated data analysis. At present, identifying the most appropriate
machine learning algorithm for the analysis of any given scientific dataset is
still a challenge for scientists. This is due to many different machine
learning frameworks, computer architectures, and machine learning models.
Historically, for modelling and simulation on HPC systems such problems have
been addressed through benchmarking computer applications, algorithms, and
architectures. Extending such a benchmarking approach and identifying metrics
for the application of machine learning methods to scientific datasets is a new
challenge for both scientists and computer scientists. In this paper, we
describe our approach to the development of scientific machine learning
benchmarks and review other approaches to benchmarking scientific machine
learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jeyan Thiyagalingam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mallikarjun Shankar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Geoffrey Fox</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tony Hey</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.12773v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2110.12773v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="I.2" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.09608v1</id>
    <updated>2020-01-27T07:26:12Z</updated>
    <published>2020-01-27T07:26:12Z</published>
    <title>Some Insights into Lifelong Reinforcement Learning Systems</title>
    <summary>  A lifelong reinforcement learning system is a learning system that has the
ability to learn through trail-and-error interaction with the environment over
its lifetime. In this paper, I give some arguments to show that the traditional
reinforcement learning paradigm fails to model this type of learning system.
Some insights into lifelong reinforcement learning are provided, along with a
simplistic prototype lifelong reinforcement learning system.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Changjian Li</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.09608v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2001.09608v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1612.04858v1</id>
    <updated>2016-12-14T22:04:33Z</updated>
    <published>2016-12-14T22:04:33Z</published>
    <title>Bayesian Optimization for Machine Learning : A Practical Guidebook</title>
    <summary>  The engineering of machine learning systems is still a nascent field; relying
on a seemingly daunting collection of quickly evolving tools and best
practices. It is our hope that this guidebook will serve as a useful resource
for machine learning practitioners looking to take advantage of Bayesian
optimization techniques. We outline four example machine learning problems that
can be solved using open source machine learning libraries, and highlight the
benefits of using Bayesian optimization in the context of these common machine
learning applications.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Dewancker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael McCourt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Scott Clark</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1612.04858v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1612.04858v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1702.08608v2</id>
    <updated>2017-03-02T19:32:10Z</updated>
    <published>2017-02-28T02:19:20Z</published>
    <title>Towards A Rigorous Science of Interpretable Machine Learning</title>
    <summary>  As machine learning systems become ubiquitous, there has been a surge of
interest in interpretable machine learning: systems that provide explanation
for their outputs. These explanations are often used to qualitatively assess
other criteria such as safety or non-discrimination. However, despite the
interest in interpretability, there is very little consensus on what
interpretable machine learning is and how it should be measured. In this
position paper, we first define interpretability and describe when
interpretability is needed (and when it is not). Next, we suggest a taxonomy
for rigorous evaluation and expose open questions towards a more rigorous
science of interpretable machine learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Finale Doshi-Velez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Been Kim</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1702.08608v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1702.08608v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1705.07538v2</id>
    <updated>2017-06-09T02:13:09Z</updated>
    <published>2017-05-22T02:28:19Z</published>
    <title>Infrastructure for Usable Machine Learning: The Stanford DAWN Project</title>
    <summary>  Despite incredible recent advances in machine learning, building machine
learning applications remains prohibitively time-consuming and expensive for
all but the best-trained, best-funded engineering organizations. This expense
comes not from a need for new and improved statistical models but instead from
a lack of systems and tools for supporting end-to-end machine learning
application development, from data preparation and labeling to
productionization and monitoring. In this document, we outline opportunities
for infrastructure supporting usable, end-to-end machine learning applications
in the context of the nascent DAWN (Data Analytics for What's Next) project at
Stanford.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Peter Bailis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kunle Olukotun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christopher Re</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matei Zaharia</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1705.07538v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1705.07538v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DB" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1911.08587v1</id>
    <updated>2019-11-17T17:36:41Z</updated>
    <published>2019-11-17T17:36:41Z</published>
    <title>Solving machine learning optimization problems using quantum computers</title>
    <summary>  Classical optimization algorithms in machine learning often take a long time
to compute when applied to a multi-dimensional problem and require a huge
amount of CPU and GPU resource. Quantum parallelism has a potential to speed up
machine learning algorithms. We describe a generic mathematical model to
leverage quantum parallelism to speed-up machine learning algorithms. We also
apply quantum machine learning and quantum parallelism applied to a
$3$-dimensional image that vary with time.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Venkat R. Dasari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mee Seong Im</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lubjana Beshaj</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">5 pages, 3 figures. Submitted to Proc. SPIE</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1911.08587v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1911.08587v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
